# LALU PRAJAPATI

**Front-End Developer** 

### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY:**

A Focused and Self-motivated Front-End Architect and developer with 10+ years of experience in building the Frontend of websites and web applications that leads to the success of the overall product.

I also like to create and share content related to stuff that I have learned over the years in Front-End development so that it can help others.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS:**

- Salesforce Commerce Cloud (SFCC), ReactJS, Redux, React Router, React Hooks, React-query, Formik
- VueJS, Vuex, Vue Router, Vue CLI
- JavaScript, ES6, HTML/HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, SCSS, Tailwind, Material UI
- NodeJS, Express, JSON, Axios
- MongoDB, Mongoose
- Webpack, NPM
- GitHub, JIRA, Agile Methodologies

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE:**

Manager (Technical Lead)

Capgemini (22-08-2022 to present), Noida

• Associate Consultant

HCL Technology Ltd. (26-04-2021 to 19.08.2022), Noida

• Senior Software Engineer

TO THE NEW (09-10-2018 to 22-04-2021), Noida

Software Engineer

HCL Technologies (29-12-2014 to 03-10-2018), Noida

Web Designer

Hybrid Coding (23-09-2013 to 10-09-2014), New Delhi

#### **QUALIFICATION:**

• Master in Computer Application (MCA) - July 2011

## **PROJECTS HIGHLIHTS:**

Heathrow Boutique	
Product Overview	<b>Heathrow Boutique</b> from Heathrow Airport offers Reserve & Collect a free shopping service. Reserve the latest fashion, technology, fragrance and more at Heathrow prices and it will be ready to collect and pay for when you fly.
Domain	e-Commerce (B2C)
Technology / Tools	Salesforce Commerce Cloud, jQuery, Azure, Zeplin, VS Code
Role	Front End Lead and Developer
Responsibilities	<ul> <li>Team Lead and self-contributor.</li> <li>Creating page designer component, custom preferences and content assets.</li> <li>Creating UI component from Zeplin designs.</li> <li>PR review and code optimization.</li> </ul>

Working closely with onsite team for module deliveries.
Working in Agile Methodologies for incremental development to deliver better application.

DRYiCE Connect (internal product)	
Product Overview	<b>DRYICE Connect</b> is a service management tool. It is an in-house development product which will be replacement of Remedy ticketing tool. With help of it an organization can maintained their service ticket category wise and a complete view with Dashboard functionality.
Technology / Tools	ReactJS, Formik, react-query, react-table, react-router, axios, bootstrap
Roles and Responsibilities	<ul> <li>Develop web application using ReactJS, Redux, React Hooks, React Router, HTML5, CSS3, SCSS</li> <li>Build custom components for UI consisting Accordion, Filter, Input, Checkbox, Button etc.</li> <li>JWT token management and implement interceptors to embed custom headers.</li> <li>Maintained high-level expertise in React state management.</li> <li>Used React-Hooks to handle application life-cycle processes.</li> <li>Used Middleware, Redux-Thunk in application to store data for multiple use.</li> <li>Implement ES6 features to enhance code standard and maintainability.</li> <li>Worked in Agile Methodologies for incremental development to deliver better application.</li> </ul>

Video Ready	
Product Overview	<b>Video Ready</b> is a framework of flexible and reusable components that help to build and maintain OTT platform. It is a professional end-to-end online video and live streaming platform with support for DRM (Digital Rights Management) and provide everything you need to publish.
Technology / Tools	ReactJS, Redux, Bootstrap, Axios, React Router
Roles	Lead Front-End Developer
Domain	OTT and TV
Responsibilities	<ul> <li>Project development environment setup and lead team of 3 front-end developer.</li> <li>Implement Recursive component functionality to create reusable component from JSON data.</li> <li>Develop web application using ReactJS, Redux, React Hooks, React Router, HTML5, CSS3, SCSS</li> <li>Used Zeplin and Invision to collaborate with UX.</li> <li>Worked extensively with API team to implement from UI perspective.</li> <li>Implement ES6 features to enhance code standard and maintainability.</li> <li>JWT token management and implement interceptors to embed custom headers.</li> <li>End-to-End feature development of Login, Dashboard, Movies etc.</li> <li>Task assignment and guide other front-end developer in their part.</li> <li>Communicating with team (manager and BA) for requirement.</li> <li>Mock-up creation with visual design team.</li> <li>Performed cross-browser development, testing and fixes.</li> <li>Worked in Agile Methodologies for incremental development to deliver better application.</li> </ul>

https://online-test.spellingbee.com/	
Product Overview	https://online-test.spellingbee.com/ is an online test platform by spelling bee which has two sections parent and admin. A registered admin can create a Test and assign it to a school or a student.
Technology / Tools	Vuejs, Vuex, Vue-router, Tailwind CSS
Roles	Front-End and Nodejs Developer
Domain	Online Education
Responsibilities	<ul> <li>Developed custom API layer to handle all CRUD operations.</li> <li>Worked closely with client to establish specification and system design.</li> <li>Use Trello to track and managed development.</li> <li>The sole owner of web app development.</li> <li>Creation of reusable and optimized component</li> <li>Performed cross-browser development, testing and fixes.</li> <li>Worked in Agile Methodologies for incremental development to deliver better application.</li> </ul>

IDFC AMC	
Product Overview	<b>IDFC AMC</b> is one of India's Top 10 Assets Managers with deep on-the-ground presence, Promoted by IDFC Ltd. India's premier infrastructure finance company set up by the government of India.
Technology / Tools	ReactJS + Redux, Webpack, Bootstrap (CSS), HTML5, SCSS
Domain	Banking (Mutual Fund)
Roles	Front-End Developer
Responsibilities	<ul> <li>Develop Login module and authentication.</li> <li>Implement multi-step form functionality for from buying to sell of mutual fund and FATCA details of client.</li> <li>Implement SSR for landing page due to SEO.</li> <li>The sole owner of Responsive site development.</li> <li>Creation of reusable and optimized component</li> <li>SEO Friendly HTML</li> <li>Performed cross-browser development, testing and fixes.</li> </ul>

	Channel4
Product Overview	Channel 4 is British, London based Public-television broadcaster that began transmission on 2 November 1982. The channel was established to provide fourth television service to the United Kingdom. Channel4 is originally a subsidiary of the Independent Broadcasting Authority.
Technology / Tools	ReactJS + Redux, JavaScript, Webpack, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3, JIRA
Roles	End-to-End Development (Advertisement)
Responsibilities	<ul> <li>Developing advertise component and content from channel and their partners.</li> <li>Creation of reusable and optimized component</li> <li>Performed cross-browser development, testing and fixes.</li> </ul>

	MyToll
Product Overview	MyToll is an Australia based digital platform connecting you with Tolls services. Whether you want to track a shipment or book a pickup, MyToll makes managing your parcel shipments easy and accessible.
	The dashboard is the hub of the site and from here, you can navigate through to all parts of the site and perform functions such as: -
	Perform a rate enquiry
	Create Shipment
	Book a pickup or view a list of your pickups
	Track shipments by reference, shipping or purchase order number
	View your watchlists to monitor shipments etc.
Technology / Tools	JavaScript, Handlebars, JSP, GIT, HTML5, CSS3, JIRA
Roles	End-to-End Development (Dashboard)
Domain	Online Travel
Responsibilities	<ul> <li>Creation of Landing page (Dashboard)</li> <li>Creation of Tabs and its content</li> <li>Advance search functionalities</li> <li>SEO friendly HTML</li> <li>Performed cross-browser testing</li> </ul>

Ray & Ban	
Product Overview	Luxottica is an Italian eyewear company and the world's largest company in the eyewear industry. It is based in Milan, Italy. Luxottica Group is a leader in the design, manufacture and distribution of fashion, luxury, sports and performance eyewear. Ray & Ban, one of the world's best known eyewear brands. The brand is best known for their Wayfarer and Aviator lines of sunglasses.
Technology / Tools	JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, WCS, google maps
Domain	E-commerce
Roles and Responsibilities	<ul> <li>Creation of complete delivery and pickup point.</li> <li>Implemented 3 step checkout.</li> <li>Error customization according to locals</li> </ul>